人类文明诞生以来
From the beginning of civilization,
我们就已深谙
we've known there's something captivating.
观看同胞为生存而战斗的乐趣
about watching human beings fight for their lives.
所以才有了角斗士竞技场 公开处决
That's why we watch gladiator games, public executions.
我们为那些依旧渴望兽性的人类创造了一种体育竞技
We created a sport for people who still have a thirst for savagery.
你刚在干什么
What did you just do?
我们的客户都是世界上最位高权重的人
Our customers are some of the most powerful people in the world.
这游戏还真的挺有意思的
Real fun game, huh?
每一年他们的欲望都在升级
Every year they demand more.
更复杂的密室
More complicated rooms,
更多以生死为赌注的游戏
more ways to gamble on life and death.
我们创造了一场终极生死大戏 请他们成为坐上贵宾
And we provided them with a box seat for life's ultimate drama.
“这是一张
"This serves as an entry voucher…"
米诺斯密室逃脱的入场券”
"…for Minos Escape Rooms."
有什么游戏规则吗
Are there rules and regulations, or what?
你们得在规定时间内逃出密室
You have to escape before the clock runs out.
所有看起来像拼图或密码的东西
Anything that looks like a puzzle or a code.
数字很重要 可以代表各种东西 各种地点
Numbers are very important. It could be anything, anywhere.
佐伊 你先走
Zoey, you go first.
他们在看 我们每一步行动都在他们眼皮底下
They're watching. They know every move we're making.
他们知道我们所有事情
They knew everything about us.
佐伊 该死的 佐伊
Zoey! Goddamn it. Zoey!
她为了我们牺牲了自己
She sacrificed herself for us!
你就是设计这个杀人迷宫的疯子吧
You're the psycho that designed this murder maze, huh?
不 我是游戏管理员 密室是谜题创作者设计的
No, I'm the Games Master. The Puzzle Maker designs the rooms.
本
Ben.
（游戏中）
你是回来救我的
You came back for me.
是的 我不想再当唯一的幸存者了
Yeah. Well, I'm tired of being the only survivor.
这不是我想象出来的
I am not imagining this.
你一定要忘了这件事
You gotta let this shit go.
所有收到邀请函的人都死了
Everyone else who was sent those invitations died,
而寄信的人却还好好的
and whoever sent them is still out there.
看这个商标 这是曼哈顿中心的坐标
The logo. They're coordinates in the middle of Manhattan.
你来吗
Are you in?
来
Yeah, I'm in.
《密室逃生2：幸存者游戏》
洗洗睡吧 很晚了
Go and wash up. It's late.
你一定累了
You must be tired.
好的 我能跟爸爸打个招呼吗 我想跟他讲讲今天
Okay. Can I say hi to Dad? I wanna tell him about our day…
不 你也知道他工作很忙
No. You know he's busy working.
好吧
Okay.
我今天很开心 妈妈
I had a lot of fun today, Mom.
我现在没空
Not now.
我们需要谈谈
We need to talk.
我交稿期限要到了
I am on a deadline,
你知道如果超时会有什么后果
and you know what happens if I miss it.
假装没事
We're not doing Claire any favors.
对克莱尔没有任何好处
by pretending nothing is wrong here.
我已经下定决心了
I've made up my mind.
我不能再这样下去了
I can't do this anymore.
你想把她从我身边抢走
You wanna take her away from me?
你想拆散这个家庭
You wanna break up this family.
这个家已经散了
This family is already broken.
我现在没有时间谈这个 我进度已经落后了
I don't have time for this. I am already behind.
等一个小时后 我忙完了 我们再聊
We can talk about this in an hour when I'm finished.
- 我不会改变心意的 - 就一个小时
- I'm not gonna change my mind. - One hour!
求你了 给我个机会跟你好好谈谈
Please. Just give me the chance to talk this through.
你可以放松一下 游个泳 整理一下思绪
You can take the time, have a swim, clear your head and then…
我保证不会跟你吵 好好听你说
I won't argue, I promise. I'll just listen.
就一个小时
One hour.
亨利
Henry?
Henry!
我不想跟你玩这个游戏
I'm not playing this game.
求你了 亲爱的 没必要这样
Please, honey, you don't have to do this.
很抱歉我刚那样说 求你了 天呐
I'm sorry for what I said. Please. God.
不 不 该死的 不要
No! No! Damn it, don't!
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
“我从泥土而生 风令我畏缩
"I grow in earth. I shrink in wind.
水会淹没我 火却奈何不了我 我是什么”
I drown in water. I survive in fire. What am I?"
真是难以置信
I can't believe this is happening.
好好思考 思考“从泥土而生”
Okay, think. Think! "Grow in earth."
（注意 98 摄氏度）
“风令我畏缩 火却奈何不了我”
"Shrink in wind. Survive in fire."
是石头 石头
It's a rock. Rock.
好吧 这是什么 这是什么 好吧
Okay. What is it? What is it? Okay.
我要找什么
What am I looking for?
快出来
Come on.
Come on!
这个颜色不一样 肯定是它
It's a different color. It has to be.
是这个
This one.
好吧
Okay.
（注意 104 摄氏度）
这是什么 这是什么
What is it? What is it?
它是干什么的
What does it do?
是块磁铁 好吧
It's a magnet. Okay.
不 快下来
No! Come on!
（警告 110 摄氏度）
金属
Metal.
（警告 120 摄氏度）
好吧 拜托
Okay. Come on.
很好
Good.
（132 摄氏度）
（138 摄氏度 致命错误　极端高温）
振作
Brace yourself!
结束模拟游戏
Ending sim.
你想重置游戏吗
You wanna reset?
不了 干得不错 我们准备好了
No. Good work. We're ready for game time.
- 存活率是多少 - 大约百分之四
- What's the probability of survival? - It's approximately 4%.
很高兴佐伊克服了对飞行的恐惧
I'm so glad Zoey got over her fear of flying.
还不算太晚的
It's not too late. You know?
什么太晚
Too late for what?
离开这里
To get out of here, I guess.
什么意思
What do you mean?
如果你想 我们可以离开
We could walk away if we wanted to.
我们已经在登机口了 本
We're literally at the gate, Ben.
我们可以去吃块披萨 看看比赛
We could just go grab a slice. You know, catch a game.
看看比赛
"Catch a game"?
我也不知道 我只是想说
I don't know. I'm just saying…
我们可以不用这么做的
we don't have to do this.
- 你反悔了 - 不 不 我支持你
- You're having second thoughts? - No, no, I'm sticking by your side.
我们能活着离开那些游戏已经很幸运了
Look, we were lucky to get out of those games alive.
我只是觉得继续我们的生活
I just think that it's okay, that we can…
也是可以理解的
keep on living.
我必须这么做
I have to do this.
米诺斯还在杀人
Minos is still killing people.
你可以不用来
You don't have to come.
不 我们走吧
No, here we go.
飞蛾扑火
Flying heroically into danger.
还是自费去飞蛾扑火
Or flying, you know, discount economy into danger.
恩斯勒 她今天怎么样
Ensler. How is she today?
看上去很专注
She seems focused.
一如既往 先生
Like always, sir.
稍等 我快搞完了
One second, I'm almost done.
我做得不错 别担心
I did a good job. Don't worry.
我知道 克莱尔 你一向很出色
Yes, I know, Claire, you do wonderful work.
希望你明白这一次风险有多高
I need you to understand how high the stakes are this time.
那又怎么样
What's it matter?
不管如何 我还是被关在笼子里
Either way, I'll still be locked in a cage.
要是我有什么意外
How long do you think you'd last down here…
你觉得你能在这撑多久
if anything happened to me?
或许你应该自己打造这些密室
Maybe you should've built these rooms yourself, then,
而不是沉迷于如何杀死佐伊
instead of obsessing over a way to kill Zoey.
她还没有准备好
She's not ready.
她觉得她可以曝光我们
She thinks that she can expose us.
异想天开
Chrissake.
或许我比你多了解她一点
Maybe I just understand her a little bit better than you do.
我们都知道失去妈妈是什么感受
I mean, we both know what it's like to lose our mom.
谢谢
Thanks, sir.
- 你好 好了 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Hi. There we go. Thank you. - Thank you.
下一位乘客
Next passenger.
（违禁物品）
下一位
Next.
请出示你的机票 女士
Your ticket, ma'am.
女士
Ma'am?
祝你飞行愉快
Have a nice flight.
佐伊
Zoey.
佐伊 你没事吧
Zoey, are you all right?
佐伊
Zoey.
佐伊 亲爱的
Zoey, honey.
佐伊 你没事吧
Zoey! Are you okay?
亲爱的
Honey.
- 你期待去越南吗 - 妈妈
- Are you excited for Vietnam? - Mom?
我觉得我做不到
I don't think I can do this.
- 我做不到 - 没事的 我们走吧
- I can't do this. - Yeah, okay. So let's go.
- 不 - 佐伊
- No. - Hey, Zoey!
停下 别走
Stop. Hey, stop.
他们说我们只能租最烂的车 但是
They said we could only afford the shittiest car they had, but…
我设法弄到了一个四门的
I managed to boost us up to a four-door.
雨刷坏掉的车
with a broken windshield wiper.
只要我们签了租车单
As long as we sign the release.
你怎么还会愿意跟我走
How are you still willing to come with me?
我想阻止米诺斯什么的
I mean, I wanna stop Minos and everything,
但我连飞机都上不了
but I can't even get on the plane.
听着
Look…
我本来不想告诉你 但是
I didn't wanna tell you this, but…
我被解雇了
I got fired from my job.
我在客户面前恐慌发作了 我们
I had a panic attack in front of a client, we were…
走出一扇门 它卡住了
walking out of a door, it got stuck,
然后我就崩溃了
and I broke down.
所以你不是一个人有这种感觉
So you're not alone in feeling this way. Okay?
而且 我对救过我命的人总是有种
Plus, I tend to have this weird loyalty thing.
奇妙的忠诚感
for people who save my life.
谢谢
Thanks.
别太感激我
Don't thank me too much.
开车的人是你
You're the one that's gotta drive the whole way.
走吧
Let's do it, yeah?
你确定不想在克利夫兰停一下吗
Sure you don't wanna stop in Cleveland?
本 我说了不要绕路
Ben, I said no detours.
我知道这要求很过分 谢谢你陪我来
I know this is a lot to ask, so thank you for coming with me.
别太感激我
Well, don't thank me too much.
我没有加油钱
I don't have any gas money.
其实我一点钱都没了
Actually don't have any money.
不 我不想在接下来的两天里
No. I'm not spending the next two days.
和你坐在一辆满是烟味的车里
in a car full of smoke with you.
（路边旅店）
我们能睡觉了吗
Should we go to bed?
- 你累了吗 - 没
- Are you tired? - No.
但是
But…
我们应该试试
we should try, right?
对
Yeah.
- 去吧 - 不 你去 你先站起来的
- Go ahead. - No, you go. You go. You stood up first.
- 不不不 - 你去吧不
- No, no, no. - You go.
- 你去 去吧 - 好吧
- No, go. Go ahead. - Okay.
干得漂亮 哥们
Smooth move, man.
好吧
Okay.
本 本 门锁上了 我出不去了
Ben? Ben, it's locked! I can't get out!
- 佐伊 - 本 本
- Zoey? - Ben! Ben!
- 佐伊 - 我出不去了
- Zoey! - I can't get out!
快点 我们得走了
Come on! We gotta go!
佐伊
Zoey!
不不不不
No, no, no. No!
操
Shit!
不不不不
No, no, no! No!
糟糕
Oh, shit!
不不不
No, no, no!
不
No!
不不不不
No! No, no, no!
操 我操
Shit. Oh, shit.
怎么了 发生什么了
Hey, hey, hey. What's wrong? What's wrong?
- 发生什么了 - 我的天啊
- What's going on? - Oh, my God.
操
Oh, shit.
我觉得你刚做了个噩梦
Hey, I think you just had a nightmare.
我看见 我看见那个
I saw…I saw the…
整个房顶就
The whole thing was just…
只是个梦
Just a dream.
是啊 我只是
Yeah. It was just…
- 我们得曝光他们 - 是啊
- We gotta get these guys. - Yeah.
是啊 我们离开这里吧
Yeah. Let's get out of here.
（纽约市）
我们快到了
We're almost there.
是一栋废弃的政府大楼
It's an abandoned government building.
没有记录 没有地契
There's no record, there's no deed.
完全是个黑洞
It's a total black hole.
就是这里 我们到了
This is it. We're here.
看来米诺斯已经破产了
Looks like Minos went out of business.
你确定坐标没错吗
Are we sure we got the coordinates right?
这说不通啊
This doesn't make any sense.
你看 这是两天前的视频 里面都是工人
Look. This was from two days ago. It's filled with workers.
一定是这里
This has to be the right place.
我们能不能先绕一圈
Can we just circle the perimeter.
再进入这个地狱陷阱般的噩梦
before we enter this hell-trap nightmare?
- 你可以待在外面 - 抱歉 我不是这个意思
- You can stay out here. - Sorry, that's not what I meant.
先停下
Hey, just stop.
等等 不要 佐伊
Wait, no. Zoey.
我们能再查一下这个坐标吗
Can we just look at the coordinates again?
也许我们看错了数字
Maybe we got a number wrong.
拜托 我
Come on. I…
我们真的不该进来
We really shouldn't be in here.
我们需要答案 本 我们都大老远来了
We need answers. Ben We came this far,
得找到答案
we have to figure this out.
都锁上了 没用的
It's all locked. There's no use.
- 不 - 里面什么都没有
- No! - There's nothing in there.
听着 我们从头开始
Look. Let's just retrace the steps. Okay?
这里肯定有什么东西
There has to be something in here.
你们好啊
What's up, guys?
你们不该来这里
You guys shouldn't be here.
不安全 这地方被查封了
It's not safe. This place is condemned.
是啊 我觉得
Yeah, I think…
我可以帮你们进去
I mean, I can help you get in there.
就是我好几天没吃东西了
I haven't eaten in a couple of days though.
- 你们能帮帮我吗 - 听着 我不
- Can you maybe help me out? - Look, I don't.
什么情况 停下
Hey! What the hell? Come on, stop!
回来 你给我回来
Come back! Come on, get back here!
停下
Stop!
拦住他
Stop him!
别跑
Come on!
停下
Stop!
看着点
Watch it!
慢点
Slow down!
别挡路
Out of the way!
来人拦住他
Somebody stop him!
- 本 - 佐伊 快点
- Ben! - Zoey, come on!
混蛋
Assholes.
回来 哥们
Hey! Get back here, man!
抓住他 抓住他
Hey! Get him! Get him!
不不不不
No, no, no. No.
操
Oh, shit.
好吧 我们去下一站找警察
Okay, look, we'll find a cop at the next station.
也许有监控录像什么的
Maybe there's some surveillance footage or something.
没必要 找不回来了
No, there's no point. It's gone.
那是我妈妈的
That was my mom's.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们应该在下一站下车
Look, we should get off at the next stop.
然后回大楼那去
and go back to the building.
那里面有什么东西 我知道的
Yeah. There's something there, I know it.
好 我们自己想办法进去
Yeah. We're gonna find our own way in.
无论如何
No matter what.
就是 新规矩 不再跟吸毒的家伙说话
Just, new rule, no more talking to junkies.
宝贝 你不会相信我现在在哪
Hey, baby. You're not gonna believe where I am right now.
不 我在地铁上
No, I am on the train.
我今早根本发动不了那个破车
I couldn't get the damn thing to start this morning.
不得不把车停在健身房
Had to leave the car at the gym.
是啊 我知道 我明天会处理的
Yeah, I know. I'll take care of it tomorrow.
因为 听着 我会遵守对孩子许下的承诺
Because! Listen, when I make my baby a promise, I keep it.
可以
Okay.
就那一次 你妈妈不喜欢
Hey, that was one time. Your mother doesn't like…
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
地铁噪音
Train noises.
我听到了
Yeah, I hear that.
（沙漏湾 在沙滩里放飞自己）
怎么回事
What's going on?
列车长不是应该在这里吗
Isn't the conductor supposed to be in here?
我不知道
Yeah. I don't know.
刚刚发生了什么
Hey. What just happened?
这不太妙 糟糕
That's bad, right? Holy shit.
宝贝 我一会儿打给你 好吗
Hey, baby, I'll call you back, okay?
到底怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
我也不知道 车厢刚刚分离了
I don't know. The train just uncoupled!
- 什么叫分离了 - 它们分开了
- What do you mean, uncoupled? - They separated!
该怎么办
What do I do?
我不知道
I don't know!
按下按钮
Hit the button!
我按了按钮
I have hit the button!
抓稳了
Hey! Hold on to something!
别乱碰那东西 做点什么
Stop touching shit! Do something!
（紧急制动）
操 你在跟我开玩笑吗
Shit! Oh, you've gotta be kidding me.
宝贝
Baby?
小蒂 你听到吗
Tiff, can you hear me?
操
Oh, shit.
这是铁轨末端吗
Is that the end of the track?
不不不
Oh, no, no, no!
快跑 走走走
Run! Run! Go, go, go!
让我看看
Hey. Let me see.
- 你还好吗 - 还好 你呢
- Are you okay? - Yeah, you?
没事 你没流血
Okay, you're not bleeding.
我们在哪
Where are we?
我的头
My head.
快 起来吧 你可以的
Okay. Come on. Get up, you got this.
小心 小心
Come on, come on.
大家都没事吧
Is everyone okay?
兄弟 你有东西漏了
Hey, man, you're leaking.
你不觉得现在喝酒太早了吗
Don't you think it's early for that?
今天真是越来越精彩了
This day just gets better and better.
你们觉得要多久 才会有人来找我们
How long you think till someone comes for us?
我不知道
I don't know.
底下的废弃铁轨有一百英里长
It's like 100 miles of derelict track down here.
而且没人知道我们在哪里
And no one knows where the hell we are,
所以要我猜 要很久
so I'd say long as hell.
真棒
Great.
我手机没信号
I'm not getting a signal.
等救援队到了再叫我
Let me know when the cavalry arrives.
等一下
Hold on a second.
看起来我们在一个废弃站点
Looks like we're in an abandoned station.
你开玩笑吧
You're shitting, right?
有人吗
Hello?
有六个人被困在这里了 有人帮忙吗
Hey, you got six people trapped in here. Somebody sending help?
乘客请注意
Attention, passengers.
请时刻注意好自己的行李物品
Keep your belongings in sight at all times.
如果你们看见了可疑的包裹
If you see a suspicious package,
请告知最近的纽约大都会运输署员工
please tell the nearest MTA employee.
保持警惕 祝你们好运
Remain alert and good luck.
米诺斯找到我们了
Minos found us.
你刚刚说“米诺斯”了
Did you just say "Minos"?
又开始了
It's happening again.
不不
No. No.
不不不
No. No, no, no.
不 我就知道我不应该回来 我的天啊
No, I knew I shouldn't have come back. Oh, my God.
等等 你们以前都参加过这个游戏
Wait. What, you guys have played the game before?
不然你以为我为什么戴助听器
How do you think I got this, huh?
他们他妈的把我关在一艘潜水艇里
They locked me in a goddamn submarine.
然后增加气压 直到我的耳膜爆开为止
Then they increased the air pressure until my eardrums burst.
所以这是怎么回事
So that makes this what?
冠军锦标赛吗
Tournament of champions?
不 不
No. No!
No! No!
放我出去
Let me out!
我不要再玩这个游戏了 你们这群人渣
I'm not playing this game again, you no-good pieces of shit!
你这样做只会让情况更糟糕
Hey, hey, hey! You're making it worse!
不要把情况变得更糟糕 不要
Don't make it worse, okay? Don't make it worse.
如果他们能控制一辆地铁 他们也能加固车门
If they can hijack a train, they can reinforce the doors, okay?
今天是我老婆的生日
It's my wife's birthday today.
我告诉她我不会迟到
I told her I wouldn't be late.
我总是迟到
I'm always late.
我应该更努力的 我应该说服你不要来
I should've done more. I should've convinced you not to come.
本 本 看着我
Ben, Ben, Ben. Look at me.
听着 我们曾经出去过 我们会再次做到的
Look, we broke out once. We'll do it again.
我保证
I promise, okay?
你最好不要抱有这个幻想
You gotta get that fantasy out of your head.
我们以前都经历过
Okay, we've all been through this before.
我们解决了谜题 我们赢了
We solve the puzzles, we win.
- 得到了自由 - 你是指 只有一人能赢吧
- We go free. - You mean, one of us does.
那是什么声音
What's that sound?
那到底是什么
What the hell is that?
不 我不喜欢这个声音
No. I don't like the sound of that.
靠 我刚刚被电了
Shit! Shit, I just got shocked.
- 你没事吧 - 没事
- You all right? - Yeah.
他们把整节车厢都通电了
They electrified the entire car?
我们都知道规则 要么玩游戏 要么死
We all know how this works. We play the game or we die.
这就是他们想让我们做的
This is exactly what they want us to do,
那就是像猴子一样供他们娱乐
you know, dance for their amusement.
我不知道你们是怎么想的
I don't know about you,
但我不要死在没人过问的Q号线里
but I'm not dying on nobody's Q Train.
乘客请注意
Attention, passengers.
请时刻注意好自己的行李物品
Keep your belongings in sight at all times.
如果你们看见了可疑的包裹
If you see a suspicious package,
请告知最近的纽约大都会运输署员工
please tell the nearest MTA employee.
保持警惕 祝你们好运
Remain alert and good luck.
我发现了一个包 是你们的吗
Hey, I found a bag. This belong to any of you?
里面有什么
What's in it?
有一条毛巾
There's a towel…
- 靠 - 小心点 兄弟
- Oh, shit. - Hey, careful, bro.
好 让我们找出来这个把手应该安装在哪里
Okay. Let's find out what that handle goes to.
所有人分头行动
Everyone split up.
- 都小心别碰到柱子 - 还用你说 哥们
- All right. Careful about the poles. - Seriously, homeys.
把手肯定是放在一扇门上的
It's gotta be to one of the doors.
把手是金属的 所以我们得小心点
The handle's metal so we need to be careful.
- 我应该找到出口了 - 太好了 有用到把手吗
- I think I found the way out. - Oh, great. Does it need the handle?
没有 这是扇活板门 肯定有其他办法打开
No. It's a trapdoor. There's gotta be another way to open it.
- 我的天啊 - 拜托 各位
- Jesus Christ. - Come on, guys.
你们没听完整线索
You aren't listening to the whole clue.
他们说向运输署的员工报告 对吧 对吧
They said report any of this shit to the MTA employee, right? Right?
那是是司机车厢
That's the conductor booth.
- 快把那玩意给我 - 你小心点
- Just give me the damn thing. - Will you be careful?
行了 我们没得选了
Yeah. We don't have a choice, all right?
靠
Shit!
希望你们享受刚刚那一幕 混蛋
Hope you enjoyed that, assholes.
等一下
Wait a minute.
- 皮革是绝缘体 - 对 聪明
- Leather's an insulator. - Yeah, yeah, that's smart.
好了
Okay.
成功了
Hey, it worked!
靠
Shit!
- 你没事吧 - 没事
- You okay? - Yeah.
玩下去反而让情况更糟糕了
Playing makes it worse.
那是旧式的地铁投币口
It's… It's one of those old subway token slots.
我只在小时候看见过
I haven't seen one since I was a kid.
好 所以我们需要硬币 有人看见过硬币吗
Okay, so we need tokens. Anyone see any tokens anywhere?
那个牌子上说什么
Wait, wait. What does that sign say?
“所有错误广告牌需要撤下”
"All false advertising must be pulled."
也许硬币在广告后面
Maybe the tokens are behind the ads?
但是广告框都是金属的 所以我们需要工具
But the frames are metal, so we need a tool to pull them off.
不不 等会“所有错误广告”
No, no, no, wait."All false advertising."
我之前注意到了一个
Yeah, I noticed something earlier.
就在这 这个广告牌是讲沙漏湾的 上面说
Right here. This ad for Hourglass Bay, it says:
“在沙滩里放飞自己”
"Lose yourself in the sand."
自己的拼写少了个E
"Yourself" is missing an E.
检查所有的广告牌
Check all the signage.
看看是不是还有拼写错误
See if there are any more misspellings. Okay?
没有
Nothing.
这 C
Here! C.
“统计数据”里少了个C
There's a C missing in "statistic."
好 C E 他们是要拼个字母
Okay, C, E… They're trying to spell something out.
等等 线索里说了什么
Wait, wait, wait. What did the clue say?
“所有错误广告牌需要撤下”
"All false advertising must be pulled."
缺失的字母
The missing letters…
有人注意到这里有多少拉手吗
Has everybody noticed how many handles there are?
- 谁会数 - 二十六
- Who counts how many… - Twenty-six.
- 跟字母表里的字母数字一样 - 对
- Like letters in the alphabet. - Right.
我们要把和缺失字母对应的拉手扯下
We pull the corresponding handles of the missing letters.
扯金属拉手 我希望大家都没有心脏问题
Pull he metal handles? I hope no one has a heart condition.
如果用毛巾呢
What if we use the towel?
不行 棉不是很好的绝缘体
No, cotton is not a good enough insulator.
包里还有其他东西吗
Is there anything else in the bag?
等等 包的内衬是橡胶 我们可以用这个
Wait, the lining is rubber. We could use this.
有人带钥匙了吗 我把橡胶裁开
Does anybody have keys, so I can cut it?
有有有 给
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Here.
有人能把钥匙递给我吗
Does anybody wanna hand me keys?
我的错
My bad.
传过去
Pass them down.
太好了 有橡胶了 该拉哪一个
Great. We're rubbered up. Which one are we pulling?
这里有个绿拉手
Hey, there's a green handle here!
我注意到另一边有个红的
I noticed a red one at the other end.
绿色的是A 红色的是Z 对吧
Green is A, red is Z, right?
也许我们从这里开始
Maybe this is where we start.
好 C是字母表里的第三个 所以
Okay. C is the third letter of the alphabet, so…
有人反对吗
Okay. Any objections?
没有 拉吧
No, go for it.
没有 你可以的
No. You got this.
一个C 第一个
A C, that's one.
看 字母 两个C 那一定有含义的 对吗
Hey, look! Letters. Two Cs. That's gotta mean something, right?
情况更糟了
It's getting worse.
- 快 继续找 - 快快快
- Come on, keep moving! - Go, go, go!
- 快放 - 没有电
- Come on! - No shock.
一定是接地了 我们还需要八个硬币
It must be grounded. We need eight more tokens.
好“释放自己”
Okay."Lose yourself."
A B C D E！
A, B, C, D, E.
- 太好了 - 所有人分散开找字母
- Yes! - Everybody split up, look for letters.
- 好好好 - 好的
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - Okay.
该死 我们要没时间了
Shit, we're running out of time.
还要七个
Seven!
看看车厢后面 那边一定有什么
Check the back of the train. Gotta be something there.
这一半到底是什么意思
What the hell does half this shit even mean?
- 这里多了一个M - 好的
- There's an extra M here! - Ok.
- 还有一个A 缺了个A - 我去拿A
- And an A! An A missing. - I'll get the A!
- M M - 准备好了吗
- M! M! - Ready?
拉
Go!
我们还需要五枚
We need five more!
我的天哪
Oh, my God. Hey!
上帝
Oh, God!
- 我去拿硬币 - 她没事吧
- I'll get the token. - She okay?
- 她没事 快去 - 代币在哪
- She's fine. Keep going. - Where's the token?
这里缺了一个K
This is missing a K!
“提前叫车” 这里还多了一个L
"Call a cab in advance." There's an extra L here too.
好的 快去L那里
All right. Back to L!
- 你找到L了吗 - 是的 找到L了
- You got the L? - Okay! I got L!
- 还缺五个 - 该死 这是猜词画人游戏
- Five more. - Oh, shit. It's a game of Hangman.
这下一定很痛
This is gonna suck!
- 怎么又是这样 - 快把硬币给我
- This can't be happening. - Hey! Give me the token!
把硬币给我
Give me the token!
快去 快点
Go, man, go!
所有人都趴下别动
Everybody stay down!
起来 西奥 快起来
Get up, Theo, get up!
- 佐伊 你要干什么 - 这是我们想要的证据
- Zoey, what are you doing? - It's the proof we came here for!
- 快趴下 - 快投币
- Get down! - Hurry up!
还缺什么字母
Where are the other letters?
还缺三个
There's three!
好吧
Okay.
（纽约市地铁线路图）
伙计们 我找到缺失的字母了
Guys! Guys, I found the missing letter…
他死了
He's dead!
天哪
Oh, shit.
- 他找到的字母是什么 - 不知道 地图烧毁了
- Do we know what letters he found? - No, the map is burnt out!
佐伊 你有办法吗
Zoey! Got any ideas?
（欢迎回来）
缺失的字母是W B和O
The missing letters are W, B, and O!
- 你怎么知道的 - 我就是知道 快去拿
- How do you know? - I just know. Just do it!
B、O！
B, O!
快去
Go!
还缺一个
One more!
我来了
I'm coming!
- 安息吧 兄弟 - 该死的
- Sleep well, brother. - Oh, shit!
快给我 把硬币给我
Hand it to me! Give me the token!
门开了
The door is open!
太好了 快走 快走 离开这里
All right! Go! Go, go! Get out of here!
快点 快走
Come on, go!
（欢迎回来）
佐伊 快点 跳
Zoey, hurry! Jump!
大家都别动
Everybody stay down!
先别动
Stay down!
我们在移动
We're moving!
我们在下降
We're going down.
等一下 刚死了一个人 我们可以缓一缓吗
Hey, wait. Somebody just died. Can we just have a moment?
也许我们应该默哀一会
Maybe we should have a minute of silence.
毕竟我们刚刚失去了一个同伴
I mean, we did just lose somebody.
你愿意默哀就默哀吧 他们一定看得很开心呢
You can be as silent as you want. They're eating this shit up.
有人知道他叫什么吗
Anybody even know his name?
不知道
No.
我叫布莉安娜
I'm Brianna.
内特
I'm Nate.
我叫瑞秋
I'm Rachel.
本
I'm Ben.
佐伊
Zoey.
地铁对大家有什么特殊意义吗
Hey, did the train mean anything to anybody?
糟透了 我们刚刚差点死在里面 这算吗
It was horrible. We almost died. Does that count?
不不 我的意思是这都是谜题的一部分 对吧
No, no, I mean, this is all part of a puzzle, right?
我们那组所有人都是唯一幸存者
So for our groups, we were all lone survivors.
所以如果密室都是根据我们的意外定制的话
So if the rooms were tailored around our accidents…
也许刚刚那个密室是为死掉的仁兄设计的
Maybe the last room was designed for the guy who died in it.
好吧 那你们的组呢
Okay, well, what about your groups?
你们觉得这其中是否有些联系呢
Do you think there was any connection?
我那组都是网红
My group was all influencers.
什么 所以你的特殊技能就是自拍吗
What, so your special skills were selfies?
不 我的特殊技能是旅游日志
No, my special skill was travel blogging.
在阿塔卡玛露营 去泰国的大象避难所
Camping in Atacama, elephant sanctuaries in Thailand.
类似这种东西
That kind of thing.
有一百万的粉丝 赚了些钱
Got a million followers, made some money,
然后就有了这道疤
and then this scar happened.
我的密室是一个爆炸的镜厅
My last room was an exploding hall of mirrors.
你这组真奇怪
It's just a weird category, is all.
我的教区给我寄了一封信
I got a letter from my diocese.
所以你是一个神父
Oh, so you're a priest?
信上让我去一个教堂之间的研讨会之类的
It called me to some interchurch seminar or something.
- 等我到了那 - 我猜猜 还有五个神父
- When I get there… - Let me guess. Five more priests?
听起来就像个烂俗的笑话吧
Beginning of a bad joke, right?
我们那组 他们是想要看看
You see, in ours they wanted to see if.
信仰能否让我们活下来
if faith helped us survive.
你活下来了
Well, you survived.
我一直在游荡 感到非常迷茫
I keep walking around up there, so lost.
我是说
I mean,
- 我真的不明白 - 明白什么
- I just don't understand. - Understand what?
为什么上帝让我活了下来
Why God spared me.
故事听得差不多了
Maybe that's enough story time…
等等 等一下
Wait, wait, wait.
当我赢得游戏的时候
When I won the game,
一个大概是欧洲人的混蛋想勒死我
some vaguely European asshole tried to strangle me to death.
我之所以能活下来都是多亏了佐伊
Only reason I got out was because of Zoey.
所以怎么回事 他们就直接让你们走了吗
So, what, they just let you all go free?
他们给了我一个拥抱 替我叫了一辆车
They gave me a hug, called me an Uber.
那真是一次非常愉快的体验
It was a really pleasant experience.
我们只是想试着找出规律 就这样 仅此而已
We're just trying to find a pattern. That's it. That's all.
既然他们在赌什么 那他们的思路是什么
I mean, they're betting on something. What's the angle here?
你不可能预判米诺斯
You can't outthink Minos.
这种不自量力会让我们所有人都陷入危险
Trying to is just going to put us all at risk.
她是这里唯一一个既救了自己还救了别人的人
She's the only one here who saved somebody except for herself,
- 我们为什么不听她的呢 - 因为我在地铁上听到了
- so why not listen to her? - Because I heard you on the train.
听起来正是因为听了她的话 你才又被卷进来的
Sounds like listening to her is what got you back into this mess.
也许我们该继续了
Maybe we should keep moving.
一个装饰派艺术风格的死亡银行 好极了
An art deco bank of death. Great.
他们在地下建了一个银行
They built a bank underground?
这也太疯狂了
This is crazy.
看 保险库的门开着
Look, the vault door's open.
- 不可能会这么容易 - 是啊 绝对不简单
- There's no way it's that easy. - Yeah, definitely not.
- 这明显是诱饵 - 是啊 还用说
- Clearly, they're baiting us. - Yeah, you think?
佐伊 怎么了
Zoey? What's wrong?
该死
Goddamn it!
安保系统已激活
Security system activated.
大家都别碰任何东西
Nobody touch anything.
是地砖 你必须双脚踩到其它地方去
It's the tile. You need to step both feet off of it.
- 踩到它会激活激光 - 救救我
- It's triggering the lasers. - Help me.
- 我来引导你 - 我不能动了
- I'm gonna guide you. - I'm stuck.
抓着我的手
Take my hand.
好好听我说
Just listen to me.
蹲下来 慢慢往下蹲
Lower your body. Nice and slow.
慢一点
Slow.
- 稳住 小心 - 等等 等等
- Steady. Careful. - Wait, wait, wait.
现在抬起你的左脚往我这边迈
You're gonna lift your left foot and bring it over to me.
对 很好
Yeah, good.
慢慢来 不急 这就对了 来我这 慢慢来
When you're ready. There you go. Over to me. Nice and slow.
压低身体 非常好
Really low. You got it.
- 我接住你了 - 再低一点 很好
- I got you. - A little bit lower. You got it.
我数到三
On the count of three.
三
Three.
- 二 - 二
- Two. - Two.
- 一 - 一
- One. - One.
天哪
Shit.
- 她没事吧 - 不不 别动
- Is she okay? - No, no, don't.
我知道 不碰伤口
I know. Don't touch it.
看起来皮肤好像和衣服熔到一起了
Yeah. It looks like the skin is fused to the shirt.
十分钟后激活
Full laser-grid activation.
- 全激光网格 - 该死的
- in ten minutes. - Oh, shit.
那是出口
That is the way out.
一定有其他方法可以通过这些地砖
There has to be another way across those tiles.
我们不能一个一个测试
We can't exactly test them.
- 也许可以绕道 - 好主意
- Maybe we can go around? - Great.
也许得费九牛二虎之力
Might as well be a mile away.
伙计们 我好像找到了一把钥匙
Hey, guys? I think I found a key.
- 棒棒糖里是把钥匙吧 - 没错
- Inside the lollipop. It's a key, right? - Yeah, yeah.
那里有很多保险箱
Well, those are safety-deposit boxes.
一定是开其中一个的
It's gotta be for one of them.
等等 我们还不知道去那边的路安不安全
Wait, we don't know if it's safe over there yet.
这就是给我们的提示
This is where the clue leads.
这里的地砖和中间的不一样 所以
These tiles are different than the ones in the middle, so…
佐伊 小心
Zoey, be careful.
时间不多了 我们别无选择
Clock's ticking. We have no choice.
安全
Safe.
好了 继续找钥匙吧
Okay. Look for some more keys.
另一边的保险箱更多
There's more boxes on the other side.
看看能不能找到更多钥匙
See if we can find any more.
“你所在的位置”
"You are here"?
不是吧
No shit.
保险箱太多了 一定还有线索我们没找到
There's too many boxes. We're missing something.
“待归档”在哪儿
"To be filed." Where is it?
（索尼娅）
- 找到一把钥匙了 - 好极了
- Found a key. - Yes!
我又找到了一把钥匙
I found another key!
- 试试另一边的柜子 - 我们去那边找
- Try the boxes on the other side. - We'll check over there.
布莉安娜 来吧
Brianna. Come on.
好吧 这得费点时间
Okay, this is gonna take a while.
八分钟后启动全激光网格
Full laser-grid activation in eight minutes.
我恨这帮狗娘养的
I hate these sons of bitches.
你们听到了吗
You guys hear that?
欢迎来到光明银行
Welcome to Illuminus Bank.
亲人去世后得到赔偿
For payment following the death of a loved one,
请输入您的密码
please enter your PIN.
密码
Pin.
我们需要密码 是什么 四个数字
We need a PIN code. What's that? Four numbers.
四个数字吗 好 我们要找四个数字
Four numbers? Yeah, okay. We're looking for four numbers.
看看有没有 该死的 都是三位数
Let's see, is there one… Shit. All these are three.
输入密码 遵循指示
"Enter your PIN. Follow instructions.
别忘了拿收据
Don't forget to take your receipt."
赔偿 公文包 在亲人去世后
"Payment." Briefcases? "Following the death of a loved one."
七分钟后启动全激光网格
Full laser-grid activation in seven minutes.
来我这儿 看看这个
Hey, come here. Check this out.
所有柜子都有数字 就这个没有
All the boxes have numbers except for this one.
索尼娅 谁是索尼娅
"Sonya." Who's Sonya?
天哪
Oh, my God.
给我 只有一个办法能知道答案
Here. Only one way to find out.
快 快
Come on, come on.
瑞秋 你看这里有东西
Rachel, look, there's something in here.
妈的 这东西太锋利了 我流血了
Shit! Shit, that's really sharp. I'm bleeding.
我们找到一个柜子 上面有个名字 索尼娅
We got a box with the name "Sonya" on it.
还有一些锋利的钻石
and some razor-sharp diamonds.
- 还有谁找到什么 - 我们也找到了类似的柜子
- Anybody got anything else? - We got a box like that too.
上面写着索尼娅 还有两叠空白钞票
It says "Sonya" on it. And there's two stacks of blank bills.
- 我不知道是什么意思 - 好的
- I don't know what it means. - Okay.
六分钟后启动全激光网格
Full laser-grid activation in six minutes.
锋利钻石 空白钞票 还有叫索尼娅的妞
Sharp diamonds, blank bills, and a chick named Sonya.
我们漏了点什么
We're missing something.
亲人去世后得到赔偿
"Following the payment of a death of a loved one."
等等 我们管亲人去世的赔偿金叫什么
Wait. What do you call it when you get paid for a death?
- 抚恤金 - 快把钞票拿来
- Blood money. - Hurry, bring the bills over here.
他们要我们把血涂在钞票上
They want us to put blood on the bills.
没错没错 就是这样
Yes, yes, yes. Yeah, yeah.
- 不 - 瑞秋
- Oh, no! - Rachel!
瑞秋
Rachel?
Rachel.
你没事吧
Hey. Are you okay?
我没事
Yeah, yeah, I'm okay.
- 柜台是禁区 - 知道了
- Counters are off-limits. - Okay.
- 牧师 去拿钞票 - 钞票没坏吧
- Priest guy, get the bills. - The bills okay?
- 没事 这叠是好的 - 好
- Yeah, this one's good. - All right.
- 把它们拿过来 小心 - 我希望这叠就够了
- Bring them here. Careful. - I hope that's enough.
好 来
Okay. Here.
- 那是什么 - 好了
- Oh, what is that? - Okay.
出来了
It's working.
〇五二六 试试 在柜员机上输入〇五二六
Okay, 0-5-2-6. Try that. Try 0-5-2-6 in the ATM.
〇五二六
0-5-2-6.
看时钟
The clocks!
大家看到了吗
Everyone see that?
停在了纽约时间十二点过九分
They stopped moving at 12:09 in New York,
伦敦时间三点过两分 上海时间十二点过两分
3:02 in London, and 12:03 in Shanghai.
那我们要怎么穿过地板
How does that get us across the floor?
等等 我们又有一条线索
Hang on. We got another clue.
是什么
What is it?
按一天中的小时画出路线
"Plot a course by the hours of the day.
按分钟数脚步
Count the minutes every step of the way."
好吧 也许这是象棋里的坐标 行和列
Okay, maybe it's coordinates like in chess. Row and column?
不 等下 我知道了
No, wait. I see it.
按小时画出路线
"Plot a course by the hours."
十二点是直线 三点是向右
Twelve o'clock is straight. Three o'clock is right.
有道理
That makes sense.
所以“按分钟数脚步”肯定是指距离
So "Count the steps every minute" must be the distance.
意思就是十二点过九分是直走九步
and that means that 12:09 is straight, nine steps?
五分钟后启动
Full laser-grid activation.
- 全激光网格 - 我们怎么知道哪里是起点
- in five minutes. - How do we know where to start from?
上面写着左起第三格
This says you start three tiles from the left.
- 左起第三格 - 至少我是这么认为的
- Three tiles from the left! - At least, I think so.
我也不知道 很多都是猜测的
I don't know. We're making a lot of assumptions.
我们总得试试 不是吗
We gotta try something, right?
等等 我有个主意
Wait, I have an idea.
你要 你要去哪儿
What are you… Where are you going?
我要给你们设计一条路线
I'm gonna plot a course for the rest of you.
小心点 好吗
Careful, okay?
好了 有效果 好的
Okay. It worked. Okay.
一个
One.
两个
Two.
三个
Three.
加油 你做得很棒 内特
Come on. You're doing great, Nate.
好了 好了
Okay. Okay.
- 九呢 九 好的 - 那是九 对吧
- Nine? Nine. Okay. - That's nine, right?
伦敦时间是三点过两分 试试向你右边移动两步
So it's 3:02 in London, so try two steps to your right.
好 第三个钟 上海 十二点过三分
Okay, third clock, Shanghai, 12:03.
向前走三步
That's three steps forward.
一
One.
二
Two.
我操
Shit!
喂 那儿有东西开了 看 就在那儿
Hey! Something opened over there. Look, right there!
这是一把密码锁 我们还需要三个号码
It's a combination lock. We need three more numbers.
三个数字 好
Three numbers. Okay.
这儿有东西
Hey, something's happening here.
有钱能使鬼推磨
"Money makes the world turn.
不要停止 否则一切都会结束
Don't let it stop or else it all ends."
这到底什么意思
The hell does that mean?
要死 什么数字
Shit. What number?
是这里的编号吗
The codes in here?
快点 是什么
Come on! What is it?
这里有国际账户
There's international accounts on here.
东京和南非 或许是这个
Tokyo and South Africa. Maybe that's it?
每张纸上面都他妈有数字
Every piece of paper in here has goddamn numbers on it!
- 三分钟后启动 - 完了
- Full laser-grid activation… - Oh, shit.
全激光网格
…in three minutes.
我们找不到了
We're not gonna make it.
大家伙 我们来不及了 还有什么 快找
Guys, we're not gonna make it in time! What else is there? Look!
不要慌 我们只需要继续找
Don't panic. We just need to keep looking, okay?
淡定
Calm down, okay?
好吧
Okay.
内特
Nate!
他要干什么 不不不
What is he doing? No, no, no.
- 内特 你在干什么 - 停下
- Nate! What are you doing? - Stop!
不 等等 我操 内特 不不不
No. Wait. Wait. Oh, shit! Nate! No, no, no.
等等 搞什么 停下 内特
Wait! What the hell? Stop it! Nate!
待在那儿 待着别动
Just stay there. Stay there.
我们不确定那几格是否安全
We don't know if those tiles are safe.
因为我们什么线索都还没找到
because we haven't found any clues.
所以你先停下
So just stop what you're doing!
内特 不要 站住
Nate! No! Stop!
停下 停下 停下 求你了
Stop! Stop! Stop, please!
你会把我们都害死的 求你停下来
You're gonna get us killed! Please stop.
不管你在想什么 这都帮不了我们
Whatever you think you're doing, it's not helping us.
没事 可以的
It's okay. It's working.
停两秒钟 好吗 我们只要 不
Stop for two seconds, okay? We just… No!
他会害死我们的
He's gonna kill us.
这是他饶恕我的原因 我知道你很害怕
This is why he spared me. I know you're afraid.
- 站住 - 我知道 我知道你很害怕
- Stop! - I know… I know you're afraid.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
- 我不怕 听她的 - 你会害死我们的
- I'm not scared! Listen to her! - You're gonna kill us!
你没必要这么做 好吗
You don't need to do this, okay?
佐伊 佐伊
Zoey! Zoey!
让他起来 快点 快
Get him up! Come on! Hurry!
他撞到头时什么也没发生
Nothing happened when he hit his head.
也许这只是柜台尽头的陷阱
Maybe it's just the end of the counters that are booby-trapped.
我们去把他从瓷砖上弄走
Let's get him off the tiles.
我们走 帮我把他拉上来
Let's go. Help me pull him up.
小心点
Careful!
好险
That was close.
- 他还好吗 - 他失去知觉了
- Is he okay? - He's out cold.
我们得背着他了
We're gonna have to carry him.
疯子神父毁了所有线索
Father Nutbag torched all the clues!
答案不在文件里 这实在太多了
The papers weren't the answer. There was too many.
线索是什么来着
What's the clue again?
有钱能使鬼推磨 永远不要停止
"Money makes the world turn. Never let it stop…"
等等 我们得转点什么东西
Wait. We gotta turn something.
- 卡住了 - 试试两边都转一下
- It's stuck! - Try turning it both ways!
根本不是要找什么数字
We were never looking for a number.
“不要停止”指的是不要停止转动
"Don't let it stop." Don't let it stop turning.
- 天哪 - 拿到了 我拿到了
- Oh, shit. - Got it. I got it.
找到了
We got something.
是个图 透明胶片 要把它放在什么上面
It's a graph, a transparency. You gotta put it on something.
可能是那个地图 扔过来
Maybe it goes on the map. Throw it here.
一分钟后启动
Full laser-grid activation.
- 全激光网格 - 我们时间不多了
- in one minute. - We're running out of time!
扔过来
Toss it over!
- 我从激光地板上扔过去 - 必须扔过来
- I'll throw it over the laser tiles. - You have to throw it.
- 扔过来 - 快 快 扔 - 你可以的
- Throw it over! - Hurry! Come on! Go! - You got it!
好 好 好
Okay. Okay, okay.
好了 你们走 我来指路
All right. OK. You guys go and I'll guide you out.
什么 不行 我绝不会扔下你自己走
What? No! I'm not leaving without you.
- 我们要人帮忙把这位天选之人扛走 - 快走
- We need help to carry the chosen one over here! - Just go.
- 快点 我们要离开这 - 该死
- Hurry up! We gotta get out of here. - Shit.
- 我拿到棒棒糖了 - 拿着
- I got the lollipops. - Here.
我来 我够到他了 小心 小心
I got him, I got him. Careful, careful.
我们确定要带着这混蛋吗
We sure we need this asshole?
好 向左移动两格
OK. Take two tiles to the left.
一 二
One, two.
我们给你留下路标
We're leaving you a path.
好 右移六格
Okay. Six tiles straight.
斜前方右移两格
Two tiles diagonally to the right.
一 二
One, two.
- 斜前方左移两格 - 全激光网格将启动
- Two tiles diagonally to the left. - Full laser-grid activation…
- 一 二 - 倒计时 十 九
- One, two. - …in ten, nine,
- 八 七 六 五 - 然后一直走到头
- eight, seven, six, five… - And then straight all the way up.
四 三 二 一
…four, three, two, one.
该死
Shit.
醒醒 醒醒 醒醒 快点
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up! Come on.
发生了什么
What happened?
我们差点失去佐伊 这就是刚刚发生的事
We almost lost Zoey out there, that's what happened.
- 你就喜欢犯傻和自私吗 - 好吧 对不起
- You like being stupid and selfish? - Okay, I'm sorry.
- 我很抱歉 - 你就是这样的人吗
- I'm sorry. - Is that what you like, huh?
本 本 本 停下
Ben, Ben, Ben! Stop!
好了 够了 他只是想帮忙
Okay, enough! He was just trying to help!
谢谢你
Thank you.
帮我们逃出来
For getting us out of there.
没关系 别客气
Yeah, don't worry about it.
怎么回事
What's happening?
这里要塌了
It's gonna collapse!
大家快跑 跑
Everybody run! Run!
- 快走 - 跑
- Go! - Run!
快点 离开这里
Hurry up! Get out of here!
- 快 快 快 - 赶快
- Go, go, go! - Hurry up!
这景色不错
Well, that's impressive.
三百六十度全景
A full 360.
- 我们之前的那组也有类似场景 - 我们也是
- They did something like this in our game. - Ours too.
但这个是升级版
This is some next-level shit.
堵一百块钱 他们在这想淹死咱们
Hundred bucks says they try to drown us.
不会 你开玩笑吧 这里这么多沙子
No, are you kidding? Look at all this sand.
肯定是地雷
Definitely land mines.
看这里 拍立得相机 上面有字
Check this out. It's a Polaroid camera and it says something.
- 写了什么 - “更持久”
- What does that say? - "It will last longer."
好像那句广告词
It's like the phrase.
我觉得要拍张照片
I guess you have to take a picture.
什么情况 刚才这有什么寓意
What… What the hell was the point of that?
- 看着像明信片 对吗 - 是 像回忆片段
- It looks like a postcard, right? - Yeah, like a memory.
照片后有字
There's writing on the back of the photo.
写的是“把锚抛在沙漏湾”
It says, "Drop your anchor at Hourglass Bay."
我们后面的广告板上有这个名字
That's the name on the billboard behind us.
拍的就是这个房间
It's just the room.
是 也不是 看地平线那
Yeah, but, no, look at the horizon.
照片里的船并没在墙那边
There's a tiny boat that's not on the wall.
那我们要找航行相关的物件 也许是个锚
So we're looking for something nautical. Maybe an anchor?
大概率被地雷包围
Possibly surrounded by land mines.
你能不能不要再说地雷了
Would you stop saying that?
请大家走动时务必小心
Can we just be careful what we're stepping on?
我去码头看看
I'm gonna check by the pier.
出口肯定在棚屋里
The exit has to be in this shack.
用X标记位置吗 说不好
X marks the spot? I don't know.
我打赌这个冰箱就是出口
I'll bet that fridge is our way out.
（把锚抛在沙漏湾）
你还认为房间都有关联吗
You still think the rooms are connected?
刚才火车上的沙滩包 银行里索尼娅的名字
The beach bag on the train, Sonya's name in the bank,
包括刚才墙面的变化
even the walls changing like they just did,
感觉都相互关联 好像在讲一个故事
it feels like it's all connected, like it's telling a story.
我 我说不好 感觉这故事说的不是我们
I just…I don't know. It just doesn't feel like it's about us.
救命 船要沉了
SOS! Our ship is sinking!
救命 我找到一个求救呼叫
SOS. I've got a weird distress call here.
好吧 我这找到一个瓶中船
Yeah and I got a ship in a bottle.
瓶中船 我来看看这个冷柜
Ship in a bottle. I'm gonna check this cooler.
看看是什么在这扇门后面
Let's see what's behind door number…
（咸蟹爪）
佐伊 现在知道锚用在哪里了
Zoey. Now we know what that anchor's for.
灯塔顶上有一个天文望远镜
There's a telescope at the top of the lighthouse.
我应该是找到那艘船了
I think I found our boat.
“盲目之爱”像邦乔维那首歌
"Blind Love"? Like the Bon Jovi song?
各位 本弄明白了
Guys, Ben figured it out.
米诺斯是邦乔维
Minos is Bon Jovi.
非常有趣
Very funny.
去找锚吧
Let's find an anchor.
多加小心 各位
Careful, guys.
说真的 之前我们怎么没看到
Seriously, how did we miss this?
- 下面这什么都没有 - 只有渔网
- I don't see anything down here. - It's just netting.
什么也没有
Nothing here.
这是
What the…
- 应该是和什么连一起的 - 稍等 看
- This has to connect to something. - Wait, look.
是个金属探测器
It's a metal detector.
能用吗
Does it work?
能
Yeah.
- 为什么还要对着我的脸 - 我来试试
- Why is it still in my face? - Let me try.
- 抱歉 给 - 让我看看 谢谢
- Sorry. Here. - Let me see it. Thank you.
之前我爸用这东西找到过一个银币
My dad found a silver dollar with one of those once.
价值一美元
It was worth a dollar.
这里什么都没有
There's nothing here.
这些人和奇怪的模型人是怎么回事
What is with these people and these crazy-ass mannequins?
肯定在沙子下面
It's gonna be under the sand.
- 你听到了吗 - 听到了
- Did you hear that? - Oh, yeah.
有东西
There's something.
- 你还觉得是地雷吗 - 慢点 小心
- You still thinking land mines? - Nice and easy.
- 是这里 - 对
- Here. - Yeah.
- 佐伊 能帮忙拿几个铲子吗 - 好
- Zoey, can you bring some shovels? - Yeah.
我们有发现
We found something.
我铲到东西了
I feel something.
先放下铲子
Lose the shovels.
来
Come on.
- 是锚 - 是锚
- The anchor! - It's the anchor.
- 拿好了吗 - 咱们去门那边
- You got it? - Let's get it to the door.
- 该死 这可不妙 - 栓住了
- Oh, shit. That's not good. - It's tied down.
卡住了 拉
It's stuck. Pull!
- 大家一起 - 帮我抓住
- All together. - Help me grab it.
拉
Go!
拉 继续拉
Pull! Keep going!
绳子连着什么
It's connected to something.
什么回事 好像有什么状况
What happened? Something's happening.
听到了吗 沙子下面有东西
Hear that? There's something under the sand.
- 几位 - 那是什么
- Guys? - What the hell is that?
去哪里了
Where'd it go?
- 情况不妙 - 那个锚
- This can't be good. - The anchor!
把手给我
Give me your hand!
- 拉我出去 - 拉住他 拉住他
- Hey! Get me out! - Grab him! Grab him!
我们在往下沉 有什么往下拉我 快出来
We're sinking! It's pulling me down! Get out!
抓住我的胳膊 抓住
Grab my arm! Grab!
- 它拖住了我的腿 - 我们没办法靠得更近了
- It's got my legs! - We can't get any closer!
- 伸手 快 - 救我
- Reach! Hurry! - Help me!
抓住他的手
Grab his hand!
快
Come on!
快 停下 瑞秋
Come on, stop it! Rachel!
我们需要什么 我们需要工具来救她
We need something! We need something to get her.
- 别动 - 我去拿救生圈
- Stop moving! - I'm gonna get the ring.
加油
Come on!
瑞秋
Rachel!
不 瑞秋
No! Rachel!
该死的
Shit!
- 把绳子给我 - 你不能下去
- Give me the rope. - You're not going down there.
你要做什么 她已经不在了
What are you doing? She's gone.
- 听我说 - 拿着 好吗 拿好
- Listen! - Hold this, okay? Hold this.
- 你不能去 - 听我说 我必须这么做
- You're not going! - Listen! Listen to me. I have to do this, okay?
内特 你疯了 停 停下
Nate, you're crazy. Stop! Stop!
拉住他 坚持住
Hold him! Hold on!
都抓紧
Just hold it tight!
瑞秋 瑞秋 你没事吧
Rachel! Rachel, you okay?
从那出来 你能做到的
Come out of there. You can do it!
- 瑞秋 瑞秋 抓住绳子 - 加油
- Rachel! Rachel! Grab the rope! - Come on!
- 你一定能行 - 起来 抓住
- You can do it! - Get up. Hold it!
加油 抓住
Come on! Get it!
好 好了
Okay. All right.
快啊 内特
Come on, Nate!
内特
Nate!
内特 快 顺着绳子向上 加油 内特
Nate! Come on! Go up the rope! Come on! Nate!
快点 顺着绳子过来 快点
Come on! Go up the rope! Come on!
不
No!
我们得帮他 我们得帮他
We have to help him! We have to!
- 绳子没了 - 他救了我 我们得救他
- The rope's gone! - He saved me. We have to save him!
把锚拿过去
Bring the anchor!
- 瑞秋 - 我们帮不了他
- Rachel! - We can't help him.
快点 他们会把这里也沉了
Hurry up! They're gonna sink this too.
快点 蔓延过来了
Hurry, it's going under us.
- 快点 快点 - 好
- Come on, come on! - Okay.
瑞秋 快点 我们走
Rachel, come on, let's go!
瑞秋 快点 他不在了
Rachel, come on. He's gone!
我们什么也做不了 我们要逃离这里
There's nothing we can do! We gotta get out of here!
“旅途愉快”
"Bon voyage."
各位 我觉得这就是出口
Guys, I think this is our exit.
这个冰箱没插电 我找到了电线
The fridge is unplugged. I found the power cord.
没有接头
It's not in touch.
或许如果我们找到另一头
Maybe if we find the other end,
我们只要把它插上 打开 就能出去了
we just plug it in, open it, and get out.
好的 好的
Yeah. Okay.
看 电灯开关像是明信片上的灯塔
Look. The light switch, it looks like the lighthouse in the postcard.
一定有联系
There has to be a connection.
值得试试
Worth a try.
因为我们触碰东西时没发生坏事
'Cause nothing bad happens when we touch things.
动手吧 我们要继续了
Do it! We have to move.
该死
Oh, shit!
等等
Hold on.
如果我们找不到出口 整个屋子就会沉下去
If we don't find the exit, this whole thing's going down.
看 看那个灯塔 现在上面出现了一架梯子
Look! Look at the lighthouse. It has a ladder on it now.
- 我去那里看看 - 我和你一起
- I'm gonna go check it out. - I'm coming with you.
该死
Shit!
- 去帮他们 万一我错了 - 好
- Help them, in case I'm wrong. - Okay.
木头堵住了出口
The wood is blocking the exit.
- 该死 把这拿出去 - 清出一条路
- Shit! Get it out! - Clear a path!
小心
Careful.
清出一条路
Clear a path!
灯光 停住了
The light, it stopped!
“我看不见你”
"I can't sea you."
门清好了 你找到什么了吗
The door's clear. Did you find anything?
有 牌子上
Yeah, there's a message.
有条信息说“我看不见你”
on the sign and it says, "I can't sea you."
但是“看”的拼写是SEA
But "Sea" is spelled S-E-A.
- 我不知道 - 下来吧 我们来弄清楚
- I don't know. - Come on down. We'll figure it out.
线索是“我看不见你” 拼写是SEA
The clue is "I can't sea you, " spelled S-E-A.
SEA？
S-e-a?
- SEA - 好的
- S-E-A! - Okay.
我去看一下船
I'm gonna go check the boat!
什么
What the…
不 不
No! No!
“我看不见你”
"I can't sea you"?
- 我不知道 - 海盐罐子 我不知道
- I don't know. - Sea salt shakers? I don't know!
好 我们来想想“我 我看不见你”
Okay. Let's see."I can't… I can't sea you."
快点 “我看不见你”
Come on, "I can't sea you."
可能和眼睛有关
Maybe it has something to do with eyes!
什么意思
What does that mean?
不是某个人的眼球
Not somebody's eyeballs.
你无法用眼球打开冰箱
You can't open a fridge with somebody's eyeballs.
好
Okay.
该死
Shit!
“盲目的爱”和“我看不见你” 等等
"Blind love" and "I can't sea you". Wait.
那个人体模型
The mannequin.
对 人体模型
Yeah, the mannequin!
该死
Shit!
快点
Come on.
该死 我拿到了
Shit, yeah! I got it!
该死
Shit.
佐伊 我拿到插头了
Zoey, I've got the plug!
不 本 我觉得这是另一条出路
No, Ben, I think this is another way out!
给 拿着 拿着
Here! Take it! Take it!
成功了 本 去叫佐伊
It worked! Ben, go get Zoey.
- 佐伊 我们打开门了 快来 - 我找到出路了
- Zoey, we got the door open! Come on! - I found a way out.
这可能是逃脱游戏的出路
This could be a way out of the game!
等等 等等 佐伊找到了另一条出路
Wait, wait! Zoey found another way out.
你在说什么 她找了另一条路
What are you talking about, she found another way?
- 这是出路 快来 - 她到底在干什么
- This is the way out! Come on! - What the hell is she doing?
- 她们不听我的 - 我们得走了 我们没时间了
- They're not listening to me! - We have to go! We don't have time!
整个屋子在塌陷 快点 这是出口
The whole room's collapsing! Come on, it's the way out!
如果我们一直玩下去 结束前得死多少人
If we keep playing, how many of us die before this is over?
我不知道那会导向哪里
We don't know where that's gonna lead.
我们得走这里 这是出路
We have to go here! This is the way out!
即使你赢了 你以为
Even if you win, what makes.
他们会让你自由地走出去吗
you think they'll let you walk away free?
瑞秋 走吧
Rachel. Come on.
你得相信她 她救过我的命 快点 我们走吧
You have to trust her. She saved my life! Hurry, let's go!
- 好 好的 - 等等…瑞秋
- Yeah. Okay. - Wait… Rachel!
- 好 快走 快走 - 本
- Yeah. Go, go, go! - Ben!
你不能作弊
You cannot cheat the game!
布莉安娜 快点 该死 快点 我们没时间了
Brianna, come on! Shit. Come on! We don't have time!
- 快点 瑞秋 - 我来了
- Hurry, Rachel! - I'm coming!
布莉安娜 快点
Brianna, come on!
- 我的天 - 快点
- Oh, my God. - Come on!
你在等什么 快点
What are you waiting for? Hurry up!
- 快点 - 我来了
- Come on. - I'm coming!
布莉安娜 我们走 快点
Brianna, let's go! Come on!
快点 快点
Come on, hurry!
- 布莉安娜 快点 - 该死 该死
- Brianna, come on! - Shit. Shit.
布莉安娜 我们走
Brianna, let's go!
快点 我们在下沉
Hurry! We're sinking!
- 好了 - 快点
- Okay. - Hurry up.
- 快点 好 你先进去 - 好的 我明白
- Come on. Okay, okay. You go in first. - Yeah, I got it.
该死
Shit.
快点
Hurry!
快爬 本 快爬
Climb, Ben. Climb.
我们走 快点
Let's go! Come on!
本
Ben!
我们走 快点
Let's go, come on!
- 我做不到 - 你能行
- I'm not gonna make it! - You got it.
活着出去
Just make it out alive!
- 快点 - 快点
- Come on! - Come on.
本 不
Ben! No!
本
Ben!
不不不
No, no, no!
我们得走了
We have to go now!
佐伊
Zoey!
不不不
No, no, no!
我对救过我命的人
I tend to have this weird.
总是有种奇妙的忠诚感
loyalty thing for people who save my life.
佐伊 快点 你得放下他 快点
Zoey, come on. You have to leave him. Come on.
佐伊 你在下沉
Zoey, it's sinking!
别这样 佐伊 快点 给我你的手
Don't do this, Zoey! Come on. Give me your hand!
快点 给你我的手
Come on, give me your hand!
是安全的 快来
It's safe. Come on.
我应该去他想让我去的那条路
I should've just gone the way he wanted me to.
本就可能活下来
Ben would still be alive.
我失去了他
I lost him.
他是我最好的朋友
He was my best friend.
他因为我而死了
He died because of me.
我失去他了 他甚至不想 他不想回来得
I lost him. He didn't even wanna… He didn't wanna come back.
这是我的错 是我的错
It's my fault. It's my fault.
佐伊 别这样
Zoey, don't do this.
是米诺斯的错
It's Minos' fault.
是他们做的
They did this.
- 不 我选择回到游戏中 - 我没有
- No, I chose to come back into the game. - I didn't.
我是说 布莉安娜没有 内特没有
I mean, Brianna didn't. Nate didn't.
他们总会用某种方法
They would have found you.
找到你和本 你知道的
and Ben one way or another. You know that.
你是对的
And you were right.
除非我们阻止他们 他们绝不会停下来
They're never going to stop unless we stop them.
你的手机还在 对吗 有车厢里的视频
You still have your phone, right? With the video from the train.
那有什么用 证明不了任何东西
What does it matter? It doesn't prove anything.
这比我们之前有的更有力
It's more than we had before.
不是吗
Right?
听着
Look.
每个人在比赛中都经历了炼狱
Everyone went through hell in their games.
我生来就有一个基因的微缺失
I was born with a microdeletion in one of my genes.
那会影响感官 我无法感受到生理疼痛
It affects sensation. I can't feel physical pain.
想象一下
Just imagine…
米诺斯会想出什么谜题对付感觉不到痛的怪物
the kinds of puzzles Minos came up with for the pain freaks.
你在反击
You're fighting back.
你在做正确的事
You're doing the right thing.
我们得走了 快点
We have to go. Come on.
小瑞 你
Rach, do…
你听到了吗
You hear that?
那边有什么东西
Hey, there's something over there.
我的天
Oh, my God.
我们成功了
We made it.
我们出来了 快点 快点
We're out. Come on. Come on.
我们出来了
We're out.
我的天 我们出来了
Oh, my God. We're out.
等等 别关上
Wait! Don't let it close!
我不明白
I don't understand.
这是怎么回事
What's going on?
我们还在游戏里
We're still in the game.
不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no.
天啊 他们对你做了什么
Oh, my God. What did they do to you?
这是酸 当计时器走完之后 会下酸雨
It's acid. When the timer runs out, it rains acid.
酸 什么
Acid? What?
我们得快点 我们要找到杂货店的钥匙
We have to hurry. We have to find the keys to the bodega.
如果我们解开这个锁 我觉得这是出口
If we could just get through this lock, I think it's the way out.
五月二十六日
May 26th.
又是〇五二六 但我们需要一个钥匙
It's 0-5-2-6 again, but we need a key.
不 但是她拿着个钥匙
No, but she's holding a key.
- 对 但这有什么帮助 - 我们只有一分钟
- Yeah, but how does that help us? - We have a minute left.
我会一直看着你 而且她是个天使 对吗
"I'll always be watching over you" And she's an angel, right?
等等 她头上有一朵云
Wait! There's a cloud above her,
所以我们爬上去 对吗 我们爬到那上面
so we climb it, right? We climb it!
- 防火通道上有个梯子 - 好 我爬上去
- There's a ladder on the fire escape! - Okay. I'll climb it.
布莉 你看到什么了吗
Bri, do you see anything?
为什么这有这么多植物 好多植物
Why are there so many plants? So many plants.
快点 快点
Come on, come on.
- 我找到了一个钥匙 扣在栏杆上了 - 快点
- I found a key! It's stuck to the railing. - Hurry!
我们只有三十秒了
We only have 30 seconds left!
- 快点 布莉安娜 你能做到的 - 我拿到了
- Come on, Brianna. You can do it! - I got it!
- 这儿 抓住 - 拿到了
- Here, catch! - Got it!
好 试试 快 快 快
Okay, try it. Go, go, go.
快点 快下来 又快下雨了
Hurry! Get down here! It's about to rain again!
好
Okay.
抬起来
Lift!
快 把门抬起来
Hurry up! Lift the gate!
又是个锁住的门
It's another locked door.
雨停了 他们重启了计时器
The rain stopped. They reset the timer.
（重大新闻）
环保活动人士
Conservation activists have.
在城市里引起了一系列链式反应
started a chain reaction throughout the city.
随着水费的上涨
With rising water costs,
城市居民开始转向收集城市雨水
residents are turning to urban rainwater collection.
雨水收集
Water collection.
- 他们希望我们收集雨水 - 环保活动人士
- They want us to collect the rain. - Conservation activists…
又一个遮阳篷落了下来
Another awning came down.
在城市里引起了一系列链式反应
…have started a chain reaction throughout the city.
好的 链式反应 电话亭上有链子
Okay, chain reaction. There's a chain on the phone booth.
好的 好的
All right. Okay.
好 他们希望我们接电话
All right. They want us to answer the phone.
如果我们收集了雨水 就能用酸把链条烧断
If we collect the rain, we can use the acid to burn through.
- 这能行 - 我们怎么收集酸
- That could work. - How do we contain acid?
- 等一下 别碰那个 - 不 没事的
- Wait, don't touch that! - No, it's fine.
- 你会烧伤你的手 - 我没事 我感觉不到
- You'll burn your hands. - I'm fine. I don't feel it.
盐酸能烧穿所有东西 除了某种塑料
Hydrochloric acid burns through everything but a certain plastic.
找找任何没有融化的东西
Look for anything that hasn't melted.
没错
Yeah. Right.
所有东西都融化了 连遮阳篷都融化了
Everything's melted, even the awnings.
我们只有二十秒了
We only have 20 seconds.
该死
Shit.
这有个番茄酱瓶子 这个瓶子没融化
There's a ketchup bottle here. There's a bottle hasn't melted.
好
Okay.
PMP 聚甲基戊烯 就是这个
PMP. Polymethylpentene. Yes, this is it!
酸不会融化这个
Acid won't melt this.
我们没多少时间了 快走
We don't have much time! Let's go!
- 快点 躲在遮阳篷下面 - 好 马上
- Hurry! Get under the awning! - All right, hurry!
这有效 这有效
It worked! It worked.
好
Okay.
这有用 这有用
It's working! It's working.
快 快 快 接电话
Go, go, go! Answer it!
- 快 - 你好
- Go! - Hello?
来 让我试试 喂
Here, let me try it. Hello?
没人听
There's nobody there.
好 当天气转好了 给我们一个电话
Okay."When the weather turns, give us a call."
这一定和那辆出租车有关
It must have something to do with the cab.
这没用
It's not working.
- 你在干什么 - 待在里面
- What are you doing? - Stay in there.
那没有足够的地方容纳我们所有人
There's not enough room for all of us!
- 来吧 试试看 - 我们漏了什么
- Come on, let's try. - We're missing something!
- 我也不知道 - 你不能待在外面
- I don't know! - You can't stay out there!
- 我们没得选择 - 不 等等
- It's not like we really have a choice! - No, wait.
我们不能这样 我们可以挤进去
We can't do it like this. We can fit.
佐伊 抓住 用这个
Zoey, catch! Use it.
佐伊 佐伊
Zoey! Zoey!
她还好吗
Is she okay?
当铺 当铺
"Pawnshop." Pawnshop!
三个戒指 把电话拿起来然后把它放回去
"Three rings." Pick up the phone and put it back down!
什么
What?
把电话拿起来然后把它放回去
Pick up the phone and put it back down!
现在在第三声铃响接起电话
Now pick it up on the third ring!
第三声 好的 一
Third ring? Okay. One.
你好
Hello?
你看到出租车了吗 那个门 门 门
Do you see the cab? The door, the door, the door!
- 好 准备好了吗 走 - 一起走
- Okay. Ready? Go! - Let's go!
- 走 - 赶快
- Go! - Come on!
- 不会打开了 他们锁住了 - 打开门
- It won't open. They locked it. - Open the door!
- 回到电话亭 - 佐伊
- Get back to the booth! - Zoey!
- 试试看前门 - 电话亭 他们切断了后路
- Try the front door. - The booth! They're cutting us off!
佐伊 上锁了 我打不开
Zoey, it's locked! I can't get it open!
- 它是打不开的 - 他们锁住了
- It won't open. - They're locked!
- 它是打不开的 - 试试看前门 试着开前门
- It won't open. - Try the front! Try the front.
我没办法
I … I can't!
- 不 不 不 - 没有地方可以去了
- No, no, no! - There's nowhere to go.
布莉安娜 听我说
Brianna, listen to me.
别让他们得逞 好吗
Don't give them the satisfaction, okay?
别放弃
Hey! Hey, don't give up!
我不想死
I don't wanna die.
我知道
I know.
赶快
Come on!
赶快 赶快
Come on! Come on!
我们的过渡滑道出了问题
We have an error in the transition chute.
什么问题
What's wrong?
只是一个故障 等一等
Just a malfunction. Hold on.
那是什么
What is that?
最终房间 你一声令下随时可以激活
Final room. Ready to activate as soon as you call it.
调出来
Pull it up.
这个设计什么时候批准的
When was this design approved?
它在你几天前送来
It was in the expedited.
更改的加急单里 先生
changes you delivered just a few days ago, sir.
这些改动都是通过这个送来的 对吧
And those changes were delivered on this, huh?
我马上上报
I'm calling it in.
不 不 不 我们继续游戏
Oh, no, no, no. We play through.
我们已经有漏洞了
We've been breached.
我们的雇主说了不论发生什么都继续游戏
Our employers have made it very clear we continue no matter what.
这是我们游戏历史上赌注最高的一场比赛
This is the highest bet-upon match in our game's history.
放松 你没事的 我把你带到了安全的地方
Relax. You're okay. I've brought you to a safe place.
你的头脑会在几分钟之后清醒
Your head'll clear in a few minutes.
我在追踪你父亲的手机
I'm tracking your father's phone.
他在来这边的路上
He's on his way here.
我去楼上试着为你争取些时间
I'm going upstairs to try and buy you some time.
小心点
Be careful.
我会回来的
I'm gonna come back.
佐伊
Zoey?
我知道你很困惑
Hey. I know you're confused,
但你要仔细听我说 行吗
but you really gotta listen to me, okay?
- 已经没有多少时间了 - 你是谁
- There's not a lot of time. - Who are you?
我一直关注你很久了
I've been watching you for so long,
我都忘了我们还不是朋友
I forgot we're not already friends.
我是克莱尔
I'm Claire.
一定要小心 好吗
Please be careful, okay?
听着 你随时可以走 但我需要你的帮助
Look, you're free to go at any time. But I really need your help.
- 所以如果你能听听我说话 拜托 - 这些是线索
- So if you could just hear me out. Please. - Those are the clues.
地铁 雨 银行 海滩 这是
The subway, the rain, the bank, the beach. It was…
是你
It's you.
- 关于你的故事 索尼娅 - 她是我的母亲
- The story's about you. Sonya… - She was my mother.
还有那个壁画 那个日期
And the mural. That date.
那是她去世的那天 对吗
That was the day she died, right?
我就知道你会看透我的一切
I knew you'd be the one to see me through it all.
那是什么
What is that?
- 是你设计的房间 - 你不明白 好吗
- You designed the rooms? - You don't understand, okay?
我父亲 他把我锁在这 他逼我做这一切
My father, he locked me in here. He forced me to do all of this.
你是个杀人犯
You're a murderer!
我尽我所能去反抗了
I resisted for as long as I could,
但我意识到我逃出去的唯一方法
but I realized that my only way out.
就是得到你的帮助 如果你相信我的话
was if I had your help, if I gained your trust.
我为什么要相信你
Why would I trust you?
- 你杀了本 - 因为我救了他
- You killed Ben! - Because I saved him.
他还活着 佐伊 本还活着
He's alive, Zoey. Ben's alive.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我在沙子里建了一个隐藏的逃生箱
I built a hidden extractor tank in the sand.
恩斯勒找到了他 他在隧道里 他很安全
Ensler got him. He's in the tunnels, he's safe.
我能给你看 看 看
I can show you. Look. Look.
看到了吗
See?
我救了他 佐伊
I saved him, Zoey.
- 本 - 等我逃出这里 我们能去找他
- Ben? - After I get out of here, we can get him.
把他救出来
Get him out.
- 不不不不不 - 等等 发生了什么
- No, no, no. No. No. - Wait, what's happening?
不不不 不
No, no, no. No.
- 他去哪了 - 不 我爸的人找到他了
- Where'd he go? - No! My dad's men found him.
该死 该死
Oh, shit. Shit.
该死 她在哪
Holy shit. Where is she?
她在哪
Where is she?
回答我
Answer me!
我不会再玩你们的蠢游戏了
I'm not gonna play your stupid game anymore!
你得做些什么
You need to do something!
我在这里救不了他
I can't get him out from in here.
唯一有权限的电脑在我爸的书房
The only computer that has access is in my father's study.
什么
What?
我们没时间了 我需要你的帮助
We don't have time. I need your help.
你能帮帮我吗
Can you please just help me?
这是什么 密码锁
What's this? A combination lock!
四位数 真有新意 还有谜题 是吗
Four numbers. Really original. And a puzzle, too, yeah?
我需要你这么聪明的人来帮我解开那谜题
I need somebody as smart as you to help me solve that.
对他来说一切都是游戏
Everything is a game to him.
他说不管我怎样努力尝试
He said that no matter how hard I try,
我一个人永远都解不开
that I would never figure it out on my own,
所以我才需要你
which is why I need you.
好 这个该放哪
Okay. Where does it go?
左边的图片关联着右边的密码
The images on the left correspond to a code on the right,
我只有三次机会
and I only get three chances.
然后我就会脱氧而死
until all the oxygen is sucked out of my cell.
- 我十八岁生日时已经用掉了一次 - 好 所以
- I already used one on my 18th birthday. - Okay, so…
本
Ben.
好 昆虫 有蜉蝣和白蚁
Okay, so insects. We have a mayfly and then a termite.
那是一种非洲堆土白蚁
It's an African mound-building termite.
它们最长能活五十年
They can live for up to 50 years.
而蜉蝣朝生夕死
Mayflies only live a day,
所以可能和寿命有关 对吧
so maybe it's something to do with life cycles, right?
该死 好
Oh, shit! Okay!
有铱 钛 锂
So we have iridium, titanium, lithium.
原子序数为三 二十二 七十七
The atomic numbers for that are 3, 22, 77.
也许是和原子量有关
Maybe the atomic weights matter.
好 好了
Yeah. Okay.
该死
Damn it!
好 希腊的历史性时刻
Okay, moments in Greek history.
特洛伊战争 公元前一二五〇年 奥运会是…
The Battle of Troy, 1250 B.C. The Olympic Games, which is…
公元前七七六年
776 b.C.
然后第三块是伯里克利
And then the third tile is Pericles.
生卒年为公元前四九五到四二九年
He lived from 495 to 429.
这些谜题都没有联系 我们有地方没想到
None of the puzzles make sense. We're missing something!
本 等等
Ben, hang on.
佐伊 你在干什么 跟我说
Zoey, what are you doing? Talk to me.
不管你怎样努力尝试
No matter how hard you try,
你一个人永远也无法解开
you'll never be able to solve it alone.
你一个人解不开 而你被困在里面
You can't do it on your own. And you're stuck in a box.
他为什么要那样做 只是为了奚落你吗
Why would he do that? Just to taunt you?
洞察之道 如果你看不到 那就换个角度
Doors of perception. If you can't see, then change the view.
我们没时间了 我爸随时会到
We don't have time. My dad is gonna be here any minute now.
你在干什么 跟我说 我们能一起想
What are you doing? Talk to me. We can work this together.
洞察之道 如果你看不到 那就换个角度
Doors of perception. If you can't see, change the view.
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
- 你看到了什么 - 是透镜全息图
- What do you see? - It's a lenticular hologram.
- 什么 - 我能看到你看不到的
- What? - I can see what you can't see.
所以你爸才说你一个人永远也解不开
That's why your dad said you'll never be able to solve it on your own!
- 它们是什么 - 是三张图
- What are they? - There are three images.
第一个是五角星
The first one's a pentagram,
第二个是鹦鹉螺的截面
the second is a cross section of a nautilus shell,
第三个是DNA分子
and the third one is a DNA molecule.
也可能是斐波那契数列
Maybe it's Fibonacci's sequence?
不 这三张图里都有黄金比例
No, the golden ratio exists with all three of those images.
- 等等 所以是什么 一点六吗 - 一点六一八
- Wait, so, what? So 1.6? - 1.618!
该死
Shit!
黄金比例是用希腊字母Ф表示的 对吧
The golden ratio is represented by the Greek letter phi, right?
对
Yeah.
- 但这两者之间有何联系 - 是小写
- But how does that correspond to this? - Lowercase!
所有字母都是小写的 所以Φ的小写是
All of the tiles are in lowercase, so the symbol for phi is…
- 我知道了 我知道了 - 好
- I've got it. I got it! - Okay.
成功了
It worked.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我不会回去
I'm not going back in there.
别这样做 克莱尔
Don't do this, Claire.
你知道你做了什么吗
You have any idea what you have just done?
你怎能这样对我
How could you do this to me?
在我为你做了那么多之后
After everything I have done for you.
现在就把我放出去
You let me out of here right now.
- 克莱尔 - 本
- Claire. - Ben.
克莱尔
Claire?
Claire!
佐伊 快 这边
Zoey, hurry! This way.
零 五 二 六
Zero, five, two, six.
佐伊
Zoey.
你能把他救出来吗
Can you get him out?
- 我在救了 - 救他出来
- I'm trying. - Get him out.
根代码太多了
There's just too much root code.
我得覆写整个系统
I have to override the entire thing.
他撑不了多久了 你得快点
He's not gonna make it much longer. You have to hurry up.
我想我做到了
I think I got it.
（系统覆写完成）
谢谢
Thank you.
在你逃出后 客人们强烈要求返场
After you escaped, the clients begged for an encore.
冠军之战
A game of champions.
他们开始让人赢
They started letting people win.
你是唯一真正击败他们的人
You're the only one who ever really beat them.
- 本在哪 - 你已经知道了
- Where's Ben? - You already know.
坐标 你一直都是对的
The coordinates. You were right all along.
你知道那地方在哪 给
You know where the building is. Here.
开我爸的车 反正他也阻止不了你了
Take my dad's car. It's not like he can stop you.
你打算怎么处置他
What are you gonna do to him?
等我跑得够远后 我就会报警
As soon as I get far enough away, I'm gonna call the police.
他会为他的所作所为付出代价
He'll pay for what he did.
但你知道他们仍在逍遥法外对吧
You know they're still out there though, right?
他们能围捕你
They can hunt you.
你来这里是为了证据 对吧
You came here for proof, right?
所以我也许锁了几扇门
So I might have locked some doors.
- 先生 - 你检查网络了没
- Sir! - Have you checked the network?
让他们这次清理痕迹
Made it a little more difficult.
稍难了一些
for them to clean up their mess this time.
多谢
Thank you.
本
Ben?
女士 你不能
Hey, hey, hey, miss. You can't…
- 女士 停下 - 本
- Miss, stop! - Ben.
本 本
Ben? Ben!
- 本 - 佐伊
- Ben. - Zoey?
她是和我一起的 给我们点时间 好吗
Hey, hey, hey. She's with me. Just give us a minute, okay?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我从沙子里掉下去后 有个人在那等我
When I went through the sand, there was a guy waiting.
他给了我这个
And he gave me this.
我不知道这是威胁还是
I don't know if it's a threat or…
我想这是“感谢”
I think it's a "Thank you."
结束了
It's over.
我们安全了 本
We're safe now, Ben.
结束了
It's over.
我只是想保护你
I only ever wanted to protect you.
你偷走了我的一切
You stole everything from me.
当年我也能对你说同样的话
There was a time when I could've said the same thing to you.
你知道在那天前我就早已失去了母亲
You know that I lost mother long before that day.
我知道她的生命在倒计时 她心里有计划了
I knew she was reaching her end, that she was making plans.
所以我决定测试她
So I decided to test her.
克莱尔 你弄疼我了
Claire. You're hurting me.
尽管如此我还是希望那不是真的
Still, I hoped that it wasn't true.
我希望我母亲能爱真正的我
I hoped that my own mother could love me for who I really was.
把它们放回去 放回去
Put them back. Put them back.
我全都要
I want them all.
我没有害怕
I wasn't afraid.
我跟随了我好奇心的引导
I followed my curiosity wherever it led,
我比你们两个都要聪明
and I was smarter than both of you.
父母应该爱他们的孩子
Parents are supposed to love their children.
他们不该把他们像垃圾一样丢掉
They're not supposed to throw them away like trash!
你为何在哭
Why are you crying?
你需要帮助 亲爱的
You need help, honey.
你能帮我
You can help me.
我不能以你需要的方式帮你
Not in the way you need.
你要离开一段时间
You're going to go away for a while.
我甚至用除掉她 向你展示了
I even tried to show you how useful I could be to you.
我能有多有用
by getting rid of her.
而你是怎么报答我的
And how did you repay me?
你偷去了我所有的主意 占为己有
You stole all of my ideas. You took all of the credit.
克莱尔 冷静
Claire, calm down.
我为你创造了那么美的房间
I created such beautiful rooms for you,
而不管盈利有多高
and no matter how high the profits soared,
你仍旧隔离 压制我
you still censored and stifled me.
亲爱的 我们能一起 我们能成为一个团队
Honey, we could be together. We could be a team.
你和妈会很为我骄傲的
You and Mom are gonna be so proud of me…
当你们看到我能做到什么时
when you see what I can really do.
- 错误 - 再见了 爸
- Incorrect. - Goodbye, Dad.
开始清除
Initiating purge.
克莱尔
Claire!